Orlando Jesig Valverde Arambula

Software Engineer | Full Stack Developer | JavaScript | Rust

orlando.jesig.va@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/septum/ https://github.com/septum/



SKILLS

Expert

TypeScript, JavaScript, React, Next.js, Docker, Git, HTML, CSS

Advanced

Rust, Bevy, Actix, Node.js, Linux, Nginx, GitHub Actions, GitLab CI/CD, Digital Ocean

Familiar

PostgreSQL, GraphQL, MongoDB, Redis, Terraform, Bash

PROJECTS

septum.io

JAM stack website built with Next.js and Strapi, that leveraged Docker, Terraform, Nginx and Let's Encrypt to make deployments a breeze.

Pushin' Boxes

Clone of the famous game Sokoban written in Rust and Bevy, featuring an in-game level editor and a top-down perspective.

<u>stega</u>

Steganography library and command line tool written in Rust, with an implementation of the least significant bit algorithm.

Bevy UI Bits

Small library of UI components for the Bevy game engine, focused on simplicity and easiness of use.

SPOKEN LANGUAGES

Spanish, English

SUMMARY

Software Engineer with over 7 years of professional experience. Created an internal frontend framework that replaced the core technology in every website of the company customers. Implemented an automated CI/CD workflow that reduced 95% of deployment process time. Expertise in JavaScript and its ecosystem. Proficiency with Rust. Generalist by nature.

EDUCATION

Instituto Tecnológico de Durango

Bachelor of Engineering (BE) in Information Sciences AUG 2013 - JAN 2020

EXPERIENCE

Applaudo

Full Stack Developer

MAR 2021 - PRESENT

- Developed an Ad Hoc Analysis product in an Analytics Suite that let the user specify data dimensions and filters, presenting the results in charts, tables and reports relevant to the organizations using it.
- Designed and implemented a UI editor to manage views on a user facing environment, allowing users without technical knowledge to fulfill their needs by creating and/or editing pages within its application instance.

4plus1Creative

Full Stack Lead Developer

JAN 2018 - MAR 2021

- Created an internal Client Side Rendering JSX framework compatible with React and Next.js components, which was adopted as the default technology to create static content websites.
- Designed and implemented an automated CI/CD workflow that leveraged Docker and GitLab to simplify the deployment process, reducing the monthly time spent in it from 30 hours to 1 hour in total.
- Developed an integration module for iCloud Calendar's undisclosed API that was implemented in a Medical Appointments application, allowing users to track and schedule patient visits from their Apple device.